Guide to the John Hicks Papers, 1950-2015 RL.00537
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John Hicks papers
1950-2015
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Hicks, John, 1941-2006
RL.00537
30 Linear Feet
John Hicks was a jazz pianist, composer, and educator professionally active in music since the 1960s. The John Hicks Papers consist of compositions composed, arranged, or performed by John Hicks; a variety of personal files documenting his history in music; and a large collection of audio and moving image materials containing concerts, rehearsals, interviews, and piano lessons with Hicks.
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
In addition, all original audio and moving image materials are CLOSED to patron listening and/or viewing. However, researchers can access the original artifacts for the purpose of reading liner notes and carrying out other text-based studies. Digital files from which CD use copies can be made are OPEN to patron use and are available for some items and are noted below. Unless otherwise noted, use copies must be made for access to audio and moving image content.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The John Hicks Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in January 2011.
Biographical Note
John Hicks (born 12 December, 1941; died 10 May, 2006) was born in Atlanta, Georgia, relocating with his family soon thereafter to Los Angeles and then to St. Louis. He studied at Lincoln University in Missouri (1958-1960), the St. Louis Institute of Music (1961-1962), Berklee College of Music, and The Juilliard School. In 1963, Hicks relocated to New York where he was a member of Art Blakey's Jazz Messengers from 1964-1965. He then performed and toured with Betty Carter (1966-1968) and Woody Herman (1968-1970), while recording with musicians including Hank Mobley, Lee Morgan, and Booker Ervin. Hicks continued with his work as a sideman in the 1970s and beyond, performing and recording Oliver Lake, Charles Tolliver, Arthur Blythe, David Murray, and numerous others. In the late 1980s and early 1990s Hicks additionally performed as a part of the Mingus Dynasty Band.
From the 1970s on, in addition to his work as a sideman and his solo appearances, Hicks also led a number of bands and ensembles. These ranged from duos to sextets and included musicians such as Sonny Fortune, Walter Booker, Jimmy Cobb, Gary Bartz, Eddie Henderson, Branford and Wynton Marsalis, Elvin Jones, and many others. Beginning in 1982 he regularly performed with the flutist Elise Wood, whom he married in 2001.
Hicks also maintained interests in composition, composing and arranging works such as Naima's Love Song and After the Morning. He further worked as an educator, teaching at Southern Illinois University, the New School for Social Research, and New York University.
Collection Overview
The John Hicks Papers span the dates of 1950 through 2015, with the bulk of the materials dating from the 1980s and 1990s. The papers consist of compositions composed, arranged, or performed by John Hicks or Elise Wood; and personal files, including business records, press materials, photographs and correspondence. Also included is a large collection of audio and moving image materials, consisting chiefly of concert recordings of Hicks from the 1980s through the 2000s, but also containing rehearsals, interviews, and piano lessons with Hicks. There are audio and moving image materials in audio cassette, LP, CD, VHS, Betamax, and DVD formats.
Long-playing records; Music rehearsals; DVDs; Jazz; Jazz musicians; Jazz musicians -- Interviews; Compact discs; Music -- Instruction and study; Composers -- United States; Concerts -- Performances; VHS; Photographs; Musicians' contracts; Audiocassettes; Clippings (information artifacts); Wood, Elise; Hicks, John, 1941-2006
- Compositions by John Hicks or Elise Wood-Hicks, undated, 2 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Consists of manuscript scores, instrumental parts, and lead sheets for works composed and/or arranged by John Hicks or Elise Wood-Hicks. Manuscripts are organized alphabetically by title, where different versions and copies of the same composition are grouped together. Most manuscripts are undated. Collection includes hand-written manuscripts, photocopies, and manuscripts produced on a laser printer. Miscellaneous manuscripts, unidentified pages, and fragments are located at the end of the Compositions by Others series.
  Many scores and parts are unbound or fragile; please handle carefully and keep pages in their original order.
  - Compositions A-Z, undated (Box 35)
    Scope and Contents
    Lead sheets, parts, piano scores, some full scores
  - 212 (Box 1)
  - After the Morning (Box 1)
  - ATM (Box 1)
  - Auvacha (Box 1)
  - Avotcja (Box 1)
  - Ballad for Mary Lou (Box 1)
  - Ballade IV (Box 1)
  - Blues in the Pocket (Box 1)
  - B's Beat (Box 1)
  - Dedication (Box 1)
  - Dedication to Suzie (Box 1)
  - Deux Battements de Coeur (Box 1)
  - Eeecks (Box 1)
  - Expectation (Box 1)
  - Heart to Heart (Box 1)
  - Hick's Time (Box 1)
  - I'll Be Around (Box 1)
  - In 2 (Box 1)
  - Interlude (Box 1)
  - Life (Box 1)
  - Lord's Prayer, The (Box 1)
  - Luminous, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Mind Wine (Box 1)
  - Minor Collaboration (Box 1)
  - Moment's Notice (Box 1)
  - Motivation / Inc I (Box 1)
  - Naima's Love Song (Box 2)
  - One Moment Please (Box 2)
  - Osaka (Box 2)
  - Peace for E.H. (Box 2)
  - Peaceful Moment (Box 2)
  - Peanut Butter in the Desert (Box 2)
  - Piece for My Peace (Box 2)
  - Pocket Full of Blues (Box 2)
  - Rose and Gold (Box 2)
  - Sea Spray (Box 2)
  - Sincerity (Box 2)
  - Slowly but Surely (Box 2)
  - Steadfast (Box 2)
  - Symphony in Blue (Box 2)
  - Topaz (Box 2)
  - Triple Image (Box 2)
  - Turquoise (Box 2)
  - Urban Moods (Box 2)
  - Waltons (Box 2)
  - Westside Winds (Box 2)
  - Yemenja (Box 2)
- Compositions by Others, undated, 5 boxes
  Consists of manuscript scores, instrumental parts, and lead sheets for works performed by John Hicks from throughout his career. Manuscripts are organized alphabetically by title, where different versions and copies of the same composition are grouped together. Many manuscripts are undated. Collection includes hand-written manuscripts, photocopies, and manuscripts produced on a laser printer.
  - Compositions A-Z, undated (Box 34)
    Lead sheets, piano sheet music, and parts. Some bound scores.
  - 24 Days an Hour (Box 3)
  - After All (Box 3)
  - Ah George (Box 3)
  - Almost Spring (Box 3)
  - Alone Together (Box 3)
  - Anne's Mood (Box 3)
  - Another (Box 3)
  - Anya's Intuition (Box 3)
  - April in Paris (Box 3)
  - Armadelle (Box 3)
  - Autumn in New York (Box 3)
  - Balcony Rock (Box 3)
  - Barrio Alto (Box 3)
  - Bay Street (Box 3)
  - Be Anything But Darling Be Mine (Box 3)
  - Beautiful Love (Box 3)
  - Beneath the Surface (Box 3)
  - Bewitched (Box 3)
  - Bidin (Box 3)
  - Bien Hoa Blues (Box 3)
  - Big Bertha (Box 3)
  - Black Orpheus (Box 3)
  - Black Sheep (Box 3)
  - Black Warrior (Box 3)
  - Blood Count (Box 3)
  - Blue Spirits (Box 3)
  - Blues in the Night (Box 3)
  - Bluesette (Box 3)
  - Boor's Back (Box 3)
  - Bright Moments (Box 3)
  - Brother (Box 3)
  - But Beautiful (Box 3)
  - C Jam Blues (Box 3)
  - Call to Order (Box 3)
  - Camino al Cielo (Box 3)
  - Carlitos (Box 3)
  - Carving in the Rock (Box 3)
  - Ceora (Box 3)
  - Charlie Parker's Last Supper (Box 3)
  - Children of the Fire, undated (Box 38)
    By Hannibal; piano score
  - Children's Hour of Dream, The (Box 3)
  - City Home (Box 3)
  - CJC (Box 3)
  - Close Enough for Love (Box 3)
  - Come Sunday (Box 3)
  - Con Alma (Box 3)
  - Coral Keys (Box 3)
  - Crown Royal (Box 3)
  - Dancin' in the Street (Box 3)
  - Dark Side / Light Side (Box 3)
  - Daydream (Box 3)
  - Dear John (Box 3)
  - Dedicated to Louis Armstrong (Box 4)
  - De Not Disturb (Box 4)
  - Don't Get Around Much Anymore (Box 4)
  - Don't Let It Go (Box 4)
  - Dr. Jamie (Box 4)
  - Dragon Gate, The (Box 4)
  - Drought (Box 4)
  - DS / LS (Box 4)
  - Earl's World (Box 4)
  - Easy Living (Box 4)
  - Easy To Remember (Box 4)
  - Ecaroh (Box 4)
  - Elation (Box 4)
  - Elsie's Smile (Box 4)
  - Elysee (Box 4)
  - Embraceable You (Box 4)
  - Epistrophy (Box 4)
  - Eretz (Box 4)
  - Ernie's Tune (Box 4)
  - Everybody Cryin Abba (Box 4)
  - Eviction (Box 4)
  - Expectation (Box 4)
  - Faith (Box 4)
  - Faith in Action (Box 4)
  - Farewell to Dogma (Box 4)
  - Feelin Good (Box 4)
  - Fire in the Hole (Box 4)
  - Flower is a Lonesome Thing, A (Box 4)
  - Fly Little Bird, Fly (Box 4)
  - F.M. Tune (Box 4)
  - For All We Know (Box 4)
  - For Heaven's Sake (Box 4)
  - Fountainhead (Box 4)
  - Friday the Thirteenth (Box 4)
  - Fulton and Lafayette (Box 4)
  - Funky Bunky (Box 4)
  - Gabriela (Box 4)
  - Gentle Moment, A (Box 4)
  - Get Out of Town (Box 4)
  - Girl Next Door, The (Box 4)
  - Gossomer (Box 4)
  - Guess I'll Hang My Tears (Box 4)
  - Gypsy Folk Tales (Box 4)
  - Hackensack (Box 4)
  - Heart (Box 4)
  - Helen's Song (Box 4)
  - Here and There (Box 4)
  - Here's To the People (Box 4)
  - High Yellow (Box 4)
  - Home (Box 4)
  - Hope #2 (Box 4)
  - Hour Samba (Box 4)
  - I Didn't Know What Time it Was (Box 4)
  - I Should Care (Box 4)
  - I Still Get Jealous (Box 4)
  - I Waited for You (Box 4)
  - Icarus (Box 4)
  - If I Love Again (Box 4)
  - If I Should Lose You (Box 4)
  - I'll Be Around (Box 4)
  - I'm Glad There Is You (Box 4)
  - I'm Glad You're Here (Box 4)
  - In the Moment (Box 4)
  - In the Still of the Night (Box 4)
  - In Walked Bud (Box 4)
  - Ina (Box 4)
  - Io (Box 4)
  - Is That So (Box 4)
  - Isfahan (Box 4)
  - It Always Will Be You (Box 4)
  - It's Easy To Remember (Box 4)
  - I've Heard That Song Before (Box 4)
  - Janet (Box 4)
  - Johnny Come Lately (Box 4)
  - Jordanian Walk (Box 4)
  - Just One of Those Things (Box 4)
  - Kabsha (Box 4)
  - K.C.Q. (Box 4)
  - Kha-de-sha (Box 5)
  - Kids Know (Box 5)
  - King Lee O's Legacy (Box 5)
  - Krazy (Box 5)
  - Lady Dardara (Box 5)
  - Lake Placid Suite Part 3, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Let's Cool One (Box 5)
  - Linden Blvd (Box 5)
  - Lotus Blossom (Box 5)
  - Love Something (Box 5)
  - Love Together (Box 5)
  - Lover Man (Box 5)
  - Luiza (Box 5)
  - Ma Genealogie (Box 5)
  - Man Who Never Sleeps, The (Box 5)
  - Maya's Dance (Box 5)
  - Meditations (Box 5)
  - Merry Little (Box 5)
  - Mickey's Tune (Box 5)
  - Midnite (Box 5)
  - Midtown Blues (Box 5)
  - Minister's Son, The (Box 5)
  - Minor Mishap (Box 5)
  - Moments for Kiamia (Box 5)
  - Monk's Mood (Box 5)
  - Mood Swings (Box 5)
  - Moon Rose (Box 5)
  - Mornin (Box 5)
  - Mother Wit (Box 5)
  - Mr. Hicks (Box 5)
  - Mudd's Mode (Box 5)
  - My Conception (Box 5)
  - My Little Brown Book (Box 5)
  - My Prayer (Box 5)
  - My Shining Hour (Box 5)
  - Native Dancer (Box 5)
  - Nature Boy (Box 5)
  - New (Box 5)
  - Nica's Dream (Box 5)
  - Nice Walk in the Park, A (Box 5)
  - Night Song (Box 5)
  - NLS (Box 5)
  - No More (Box 5)
  - No More Goodbyes (Box 5)
  - No One Has To Know (Box 5)
  - Nuvola (Box 5)
  - October song (Box 5)
  - Ode for Aaron (Box 5)
  - Off Minor (Box 5)
  - Ojos de Rojo (Box 5)
  - Old Country, The (Box 5)
  - One for Amos (Box 5)
  - One for E.W. (Box 5)
  - Ornate (Box 5)
  - O.T.Y.O.G. (Box 5)
  - Our Second Father (Box 5)
  - Pannonica (Box 5)
  - Paris Without Shelly (Box 5)
  - Passion Flower (Box 5)
  - Peaceful Moment, A (Box 5)
  - Peanut Butter Two (Box 5)
  - Phooey (Box 5)
  - Pick Yourself Up (Box 5)
  - Piece of My Heart (Box 5)
  - Plain and Simple Truth (Box 5)
  - Poem, The (Box 5)
  - Portrait (Box 6)
  - Prayer for Peace (Box 6)
  - Product #19 (Box 6)
  - Raincheck (Box 6)
  - Raise Up (Box 6)
  - Reflections (Box 6)
  - Revealing (Box 6)
  - Reverence (Box 6)
  - Rhapsody and Blues (Box 6)
  - Right On (Box 6)
  - River Jordan (Box 6)
  - Rose Without a Thorn, A (Box 6)
  - Ruby (Box 6)
  - Ruby My Dear (Box 6)
  - Saigon-Phunk (Box 6)
  - Sail Away (Box 6)
  - Samurai, The (Box 6)
  - Say It Over Again (Box 6)
  - Saxaceous Serenade (Box 6)
  - Sensation (Box 6)
  - Shine (Box 6)
  - Shoulders (Box 6)
  - Siempre me Amor (Box 6)
  - Silk 'n' Satin (Box 6)
  - Sister Daisy (Box 6)
  - Sleeping Bee, A (Box 6)
  - So In Love (Box 6)
  - Some Wondering Bushmen (Box 6)
  - Somebody Gotta Move (Box 6)
  - Someone To Watch (Box 6)
  - Song of Love (Box 6)
  - Songs of the Underground Railroad (Box 6)
  - Soul Eyes (Box 6)
  - Soul Train (Box 6)
  - South of the Border (Box 6)
  - Spaces Revisited (Box 6)
  - Spain (Box 6)
  - Spanning (Box 6)
  - Star Crossed Lovers (Box 6)
  - Stay Straight (Box 6)
  - Steam (Box 6)
  - Stompin' at the Savoy (Box 6)
  - Storm Cloud Waltz Again (Box 6)
  - Summertime (Box 6)
  - Surge (Box 6)
  - Surged (Box 6)
  - Suspicion (Box 6)
  - Sweet Love of Mine (Box 6)
  - Symphony in Blue (Box 6)
  - Take the A Train (Box 6)
  - Tell Me You Love Me (Box 6)
  - Textures (Box 6)
  - That's for Me (Box 6)
  - Theme for Delores (Box 6)
  - Theme for Tet Offensive (Box 6)
  - Then I Found You, And (Box 6)
  - There But for the Grace of (Box 6)
  - Three Elders (Box 6)
  - Time on My Hand (Box 6)
  - Times Slimes (Box 6)
  - Tiptoe Gently Thru My Dreams (Box 6)
  - To A.P. Kern (Box 6)
  - To See Her Face (Box 6)
  - Tomorrow Will Be Another Day (Box 6)
  - Tonight at Noon (Box 6)
  - Traveling Woman, The (Box 6)
  - Triste (Box 6)
  - Tunnel Rat (Box 6)
  - Turn Around, The (Box 6)
  - Ugly Beauty (Box 6)
  - Valse Macabre (Box 6)
  - Vera (Box 6)
  - Walkin' Shoes (Box 6)
  - Waltz for Maddie (Box 6)
  - Waltz for Zweetie (Box 6)
  - Wanderer, The (Box 6)
  - We'll Be Together Again (Box 6)
  - Well Water (Box 6)
  - What a Diff'rence a Day Made (Box 6)
  - What Your Name (Box 6)
  - Wheel (Box 6)
  - Wide Open (Box 6)
  - Wise One (Box 6)
  - With Malice Toward None (Box 7)
  - Wynton (Box 7)
  - Yesterday's Rainbow (Box 7)
  - Yo... Ho Chi (Box 7)
  - You Go To My Head (Box 7)
  - You Know I Care (Box 7)
  - You Must Believe in Spring (Box 7)
  - Your Mind is on Vacation (Box 7)
  - You're My Thrill (Box 7)
  - Yvette (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous Lead Sheets, 4 folders (Box 7)
  - [unlabeled] (Box 7)
- Oversized Compositions, undated, 1 box
  Consists of manuscript scores and instrumental parts for compositions composed and/or arranged by John Hicks, Elise Wood-Hicks, and others. Manuscripts are organized alphabetically by title.
  - After the Morning, arr. John Hicks (Box 8)
  - Arulu (Box 8)
  - Children of the Fire (Box 8)
  - Daydream, arr. Elise Wood-Hicks (Box 8)
  - Gypsy Folk Tales, arr. Mickey Bass (Box 8)
  - Isfahan, arr. John Hicks (Box 8)
  - Naima's Love Song, arr. John Hicks (Box 8)
  - Piece For My Peace, arr. John Hicks (Box 8)
  - Ruby My Dear, arr. Mickey Bass (Box 8)
  - String Quartet (Box 8)
  - Supplication, arr. John Hicks (Box 8)
  - Surrey, arr. John Hicks (Box 8)
  - Urban Moods, arr. John Hicks (Box 8)
- Personal Files, 1950-2015, 20 boxes
  Consists of business records, contracts, itineraries, promotional materials, reviews and press clippings, photographs, and correspondence kept by John Hicks throughout his career. Papers were kept in original order with original folder titles when possible. Many papers are undated.
  - John Hicks Bio (Box 9)
  - John Hicks Performance Bio (Box 9)
  - Elise Bio (Box 9)
  - Bio - E Woods (Box 9)
  - Other Bios (Box 9)
  - Hicks Memorial Service (Box 9)
  - Obituaries (Box 9)
  - Street Co-Naming 2010 (Box 9)
  - John Hicks Legacy Band (Box 9)
  - Publicity Materials (Box 9)
  - Itineraries, 6 folders (Box 10)
  - Performance Flyers, 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Concert Programs, 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Concert Programs, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Potential Gigs (Box 12)
  - Repertoire (Box 12)
  - German Tour (Box 13)
  - Israel (Box 13)
  - Polish Artists Agency (Box 13)
  - Romania (Box 13)
  - Barry Wallenstein (Box 13)
  - Michael Geautier (Box 13)
  - Blues Alley (Box 13)
  - Carnegie Hall (Box 13)
  - Billy Strayhorn - Aaron Davis Hall (Box 13)
  - Kennedy Center (Box 13)
  - St. Mark's United Methodist Church (Box 13)
  - John Hicks/Jay McShann (Box 13)
  - JH 7/12-18 (Box 13)
  - Calif. Tour '98 (Box 13)
  - Pori Jazz (Box 13)
  - Press Kit #1 (Box 14)
  - Press Kit #2 - General Info (Box 14)
  - Press Kit #3 - Basic (Box 14)
  - Press Kit Materials (Box 14)
  - Press Releases (Box 14)
  - Press - Originals (Box 14)
  - Original Paste-Ups (Publicity) (Box 14)
  - In the Mix (promo) (Box 14)
  - Single Petal of a Rose (promo) (Box 14)
  - IREC (Box 14)
  - Bruce Hopewell (Box 14)
  - Six Continents Club (Box 14)
  - Memos '78 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence 1999 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence 2000 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence 2001 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, 1993-2006 (Box 38)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 5 folders (Box 15)
  - John Hicks - Written Notes (Box 16)
  - Letters of Appreciation (Box 16)
  - JoAnn Collins Thesis on John Hicks (Box 16)
  - JH/EW Reviews 1984-1990 (Box 16)
  - John Hicks Reviews 1991-1992 (Box 16)
  - CD Reviews (Box 16)
  - Jazz Times Reviews (Box 16)
  - EW Reviews (Box 16)
  - Reviews/Newspaper Clippings (Box 16)
  - Articles - Originals (Box 16)
  - Press - Various (Box 16)
  - Magazine Articles (Box 17)
  - Articles - General Artists (Box 17)
  - Magazines (Box 17)
  - NYU Clippings - Chicago, DC (Box 17)
  - Interviews (Box 17)
  - Jazz Media Lists (Box 17)
  - Mailing/Media Lists (Box 17)
  - Mailing List - National, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Jazz Listings (Box 18)
  - Jazz Productions (Box 18)
  - Jazz Workshop (Box 18)
  - Baldwin Pianos (Box 18)
  - Bluther Recital Piano (Box 18)
  - Stage Plan (Box 18)
  - World Music Workshop (Box 18)
  - Beautiful Friendship (Box 18)
  - Bluport Sound/Jim Merod (Box 18)
  - Concord Jazz (Box 18)
  - Concord Records (Box 18)
  - Disk Union, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - DSM Records, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Enja (Box 18)
  - Fantasy Records (Box 19)
  - Highnote Records, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Hiwood (Box 19)
  - Keystone Korner (Box 19)
  - Landmark Records (Box 19)
  - Lovano Productions (Box 19)
  - Noble Music (Box 19)
  - Bob Thiele - Red Baron (Box 19)
  - Reservoir Music (Box 19)
  - Rigel Arts, Taiwan (Box 19)
  - Theresa Records (Box 19)
  - Theresa Press Reviews (Box 19)
  - Harry Fox Agency, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Beldock/Najamia Music (Box 20)
  - Destination Productions (Box 20)
  - Granting Organizations (Box 20)
  - Grant Proposals, 3 folders (Box 20)
  - Meet the Composer Grant (Box 20)
  - NEA Grant Application (Box 20)
  - Contracts, 1983-1993, 3 folders (Box 21)
  - Contracts, 1990s (Box 21)
  - Contracts, 1993 (Box 21)
  - Contracts, 1996 (Box 21)
  - Contracts, 1998 (Box 21)
  - Contracts, 1999 (Box 21)
  - Contracts, 2001 (Box 22)
  - Contracts, 2003 (Box 22)
  - Riders/Contracts (Box 22)
  - Licensing - Najamia Publishing (Box 22)
  - Music Stuff (Box 22)
  - Associated Community Teams (Box 22)
  - Manhattan Plaza (Box 22)
  - Computer Info (Box 22)
  - Computer Notes (Box 22)
  - Computer 2001 (Box 22)
  - BMI, 7 folders (Box 23)
  - Foreign Publishing (Box 24)
  - Mechanicals (Box 24)
  - HicksWood.com (Box 24)
  - Hicks/Wood (Box 24)
  - Blank Contracts (Box 24)
  - Evidence Music, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Mapleshade, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Pay Stubs (Box 25)
  - Receipts, 1999 (Box 25)
  - Mileage Statements (Box 25)
  - Luminous (Box 25)
  - Bills (Box 25)
  - Ledger Entries (Box 25)
  - Paystubs/Timesheets (Box 25)
  - Royalty Statements (Box 25)
  - Local 802 Statements (Box 25)
  - Charitable Donations (Box 25)
  - Hotels/Charges 2002 (Box 25)
  - Pension (Box 25)
  - American Federation of Musicians (Box 25)
  - Master Recordings (Box 25)
  - [untitled], 5 folders (Box 25)
  - Calendars and Journals, 1986-2005 (Box 26)
    Appointment calendars, notebooks, and one scrapbook related to John Hicks.
  - Photographs (Box 27)
    Miscellaneous candid and publicity photographs of John Hicks and various associates from throughout his life.
  - Painting of John Hicks (Box 33)
  - Poster of John Hicks, undated (Box 37)
  - Assorted Concert Posters for John Hicks and Elise Wood, 1991-2005 and undated (Box 37)
    Includes posters for a variety of domestic and international performances, particularly in Europe and Asia
  - Contracts, 2010 (Box 35)
  - Correspondence, 1992-2002 and undated (Box 35)
  - Festival Badges, 2000-2005 (Box 35)
  - Hicks-Murray Slides, undated (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous Articles, 1989-2015 and undated (Box 35)
    Playing techniques, Thelonious Monk Jazz Institute, jazz standards lists
  - Miscellaneous Drawings, undated (Box 35)
  - Music Books, 1985-2008; 5 folders (Box 35)
    Assorted bound texts, including score anthologies and arranging guides
  - Photographs, undated (Box 35)
    Miscellaneous photographs, including John Hicks headshot. Includes two picture compact discs.
  - Poetry and Song Lyrics, undated (Box 35)
    Includes lyrics to several songs by John Hicks.
  - Press Clippings, 1984-2012 and undated (Box 35)
    Various newspaper clipping photocopies. Includes one issue of New York City Jazz Record. Also includes press booklet on Christian Lotto.
  - Programs, 2010-2011 (Box 35)
  - Scrapbook, 1978-1992 and undated (Box 35)
    Contents of binder. Includes photographs, press clippings, and sets lists.
  - Set Lists, 2003-2009 and undated (Box 35)
    Set lists for various performances.
  - Sketchbooks, 1978-2002 and undated (Box 35)
    Music sketchbooks with various pieces and musical figures notated.
  - Elizabeth Johnson Harris Memoir, 1922 and undated (Box 38)
    Includes photographs, newspaper clippings, souvenir program
  - Assorted headshots of John Hicks and Elise Wood, family snapshots, 1991-2005 and undated (Box 38)
  - Assorted programs and publicity materials, 1970-2006 and undated (Box 38)
    Includes posters, flyers, newspaper clippings
  - BMI Jazz Pioneer award, undated (Box 38)
    Gold-colored music note sculpture
- Audio and Moving Image Materials, 1975-2006 and undated, 5 boxes
  Series contains audio and moving image materials in audio cassette, LP, CD, VHS, Betamax, and DVD formats. Consists chiefly of recordings of John Hicks's concert performances from the 1980s through the 2000s, but also contains rehearsals, interviews and piano lessons with Hicks, and a DVD shown at Hicks's memorial service.
  Conditions Governing Access note
  RESTRICTIONS: All original audio and moving image materials are CLOSED to patron use. CD or DVD use copies, which are OPEN to patron use, can be made for those items noted below as being housed on the digital audio server. Unless otherwise noted, use copies must be made for access to content.
  - Audio Cassettes
    Original cassette titles retained.
    - Hicks/O'Reilly Interview (5/27/86) (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-001)
    - Interview by Jazz Hihyo Magazine (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-002)
    - Hicks/Wood Interviews JH Trio w/ Sylvia (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-003)
    - John Hicks History (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-004)
    - His Story (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-005)
    - Lesson with John Hicks 7-3-98 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-006)
    - Lesson with John Hicks 3.22.03 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-007)
    - Lesson with John Hicks 7-2-99 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-008)
    - Lesson with John Hicks 10-2-99 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-009)
    - John Hicks Piano / M. Bernstein Alto (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-010)
    - John Hicks / Elise Wood / Walter Booker (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-011)
    - Carnegie Recital Hall John Hicks, Wood, Booker, Nov 15, 1985 (Box 28, Item 2011-0007-012)